Welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So, I've talked a lot on
slavery and the African slave trade in
colonies, and it's because that slavery
was a massive aspect of colonies. In
topic 2.7, we move away from the
connotation of slavery and talk about
other societies cultures. The fact is,
in all European colonies, there existed
lots of different religions and ethnic
groups, causing acceptance of diversity
in colonies, and the word for that is
pluralism, along with varying degrees of
intellectual exchange. European leaders
saw their colonies in the Americas as
money makers and nothing else. The
actual truth was that these colonies
made their own unique culture and way of
democratic governance. European leaders
continued to clash with their colonies
on things like the Navigation Acts,
which lowered trade with their colonies
and ended up hurting the colonies. The
Enlightenment also started in Europe,
which was an intellectual movement of
reason and science. This would have a
heavy influence on colonists later when
the revolution would start with the
ideas like freedom of religion and
equality. But, in this video, all you
need to know is the initial response to
the Enlightenment in the colonies, which
was the First Great Awakening. This
occurred in the colonies where it saw
the revival of Christianity in the
British 13 colonies. This Christianity
was traditionally the British's form,
being Anglicanism, but it shifted
throughout decades in the First Great
Awakening to branches of Protestantism,
like Baptists and Methodists. We also
see a rise and the spread of Protestant
Evangelicalism. The transatlantic print
culture also started in the colonies
where you start seeing the communication
via press. The fact is that this culture
had a different way of life, government,
and reason that differed from European
thought. Europeans didn't really like
this and frequently clashed with their
colonies. That, however, is something to
talk about next unit. For now, here are
your AP style questions for this topic.
Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
See you in the next one.